[theme music playing]
[gunshots]
[gun clicks, fires]
[whoosh, slashing sounds]
[machine gun fire]
[machine gun fire continues]
[single gunshot]
[rapid gunfire]
[echoing blast]
[blade whooshing]
[tense music builds]
[Marlon] Friends, gather all
the citizens of Ardiente.
Even the Ardiente loyalists.
Call the press so the whole world
can see the ruthlessness of the Ardientes.
[woman] Justice for the
victims of the Ardientes!
[man] It's time for retribution.
Down with the Ardientes!
Thank you for gathering
the townspeople today.
Now they can see just how
tainted your souls really are!
Arrest them! Arrest them all!
-[gunshots and screams]
-Papa!
[Julio] You ruined Ardiente.
This is your fault!
[chair clatters]
-Lily! Lily!
-[crowd] Long live!
[cheers and applause]
[Julio] Secure the perimeter.
I don't want any intruders in this house.
I'm sorry to say this,
but we've lost many of our men.
Most have surrendered, and many are hurt.
[Julio] I don't give a damn!
No one comes into my fortress.
Because this house is unsinkable.
I am unsinkable!
[Sanggano] Men, stand down!
-Governor!
-Colonel!
Get inside! Please!
[Emilia] Enough, Papa. Enough!
We have to go!
The whole house is surrounded!
[Julio] Pigs!
Pathetic ingrates!
[crowd clamoring]
Ooh. [chuckles]
Now, this…
This is revenge.
And it tastes so sweet.
I never tasted revenge like this.
It tastes so delicious.
It actually tastes like honey.
But
I must apologize to everyone
for being fashionably late.
Because I was dealing with my emotions.
My loneliness.
With Arnaldo…
Then, Raul…
And now, Madrigal.
But
I'm back.
And I guess it's better late
than never, right?
[chuckles]
I wish I was as cutthroat as Lily Cruz.
For some reason, she makes revenge look so
fashionable and possible.
But this is exactly what I want.
This is perfect.
Angelo, take me to the back.
And I'll give the Ardientes
a little surprise.
Yes, Lady N.
[chuckles]
[engine rumbles]
[Emilia] Let's go, Papa.
[Natalie] What's the rush, evil witch?
Natalie?
You, crazy witch!
And what the hell are you doing here, huh?
We already have our plate full
at the mansion.
We don't have time for you.
I know!
I saw, and that's why I'm here.
I want to enjoy this moment.
Poor Emilia.
Poor Ardientes.
I was thinking to myself,
what were you both thinking, huh?
After all the mortal sins
that you and your family did?
Your daughter killed my father!
Hey! And look who's talking, huh?
Wasn't cheating with my husband
revenge enough for you?
You killed your own husband!
You murderer!
Emilia, just cut the drama
and kill her already!
Go back there, Papa!
You crazy woman!
Come on!
Isn't this what you wanted?!
You wanted us to kill each other!
-You witch… [screams]
-[gunshot]
What are you doing?
Everyone, guess who's here!
The Ardientes!
-You crazy witch!
-They're here!
-Shoot!
-The Ardientes are here!
-[Emilia] This--
-Hey, guys!
Come here, everyone!
Over here, everyone!
-There they are!
-Hurry!
That serves you right, you evil witch!
Do what you cowards do best,
other than stabbing people
on their backs literally.
Run, run as fast as you can.
And don't even dare coming back!
Daddy, I know you're proud
of your little girl.
Justice has been served.
And it tastes so delicious.
I love you, Daddy.
[tense music playing]
This can't be happening, Papa.
This can't be happening.
In the blink of an eye,
we lost our fortune,
our power, and our province.
What are we going to do now?
We are not leaving Poblacion Ardiente.
I built this town.
I own this town.
I am this town!
Papa, this province destroyed us.
The people here no longer want us!
Where do we go now?
Oh, shut up, Emilia!
Don't think I've forgotten.
It was your actions that brought
Lily Cruz into our lives.
Now, look.
See how the mighty have fallen.
This is because of the
useless women in my life.
I'm the father of this town.
I gave them everything.
I gave them Poblacion Ardiente.
And this is how they repay me?
By storming my mansion like a plague!
What a bunch of lowlife ingrates!
We will not leave this town.
I will never let a woman
and a bastard take my place!
No.
I will not accept defeat!
Stop the car. Stop it right now!
-What?
-Stop it!
[tires screech]
[car door opens]
[handbrake clicks]
[ominous music playing]
I never thought it would come to this.
That a single wildflower…
would take down a king like me.
We created the monster
of our own destruction, Papa.
And that monster is that witch, Lily Cruz.
Born from your jealousy.
You had Dante Cruz killed…
to stop him from investigating.
You were just trying to protect
my name and our family.
And in the process…
you also protected the people
of Poblacion Ardiente.
But Papa,
the people who loved us before
will never forgive us again.
It's over, Papa. We have
nothing to come back to.
Forgiveness is overrated.
What matters most is fear.
Sadly, they do not fear us anymore.
[ominous music continues]
I shed blood, sweat, and tears
to establish Poblacion Ardiente.
So…
Blood, sweat, and tears will spill
over the land they took from me.
[ominous music playing]
WELCOME TO POBLACION ARDIENTE
[car door closes]
[engine starts]
[ominous music continues]
[bright music playing]
[Lily] With every smile they show…
with every hug and
expression of gratitude…
I'm reminded of the reason
why I kept fighting.
So that there will never be
victims of abuse and violence again.
No more shattered dreams
and victims of injustice.
No more broken families.
[uplifting music playing]
[crowd cheering]
I kept fighting for those who
dreamt of freedom and change.
I kept fighting so no one
will ever have to experience
the suffering I went through.
[cheers and indistinct chatter]
If this is the reward for
everything we went through,
then it was worth it.
[crowd chanting] Diego! Diego! Diego!
[chanting continues]
[Georgina] Camia, the witnesses are here.
They're ready to support Lily and Diego.
Thank you, Attorney.
Arthur?
Arthur.
Where are you going?
I'm leaving this place.
The scars that the Ardientes
inflicted on me are too deep.
I don't think I can
still go on living here.
That's why we're here.
So we can help you.
[sighs]
You've already done enough.
The kindness you've shown me
is already enough.
But your trust…
The trust that you and Lily have given me…
A person like me doesn't deserve that
after everything I did to you.
After I ruined both of your lives.
Arthur, you were a victim too.
We were all victims of the Ardientes.
I did what I did because I was a coward.
And, I think, if I stay here,
I'll forever be haunted by my conscience.
What's done is done.
What's important is that no more lives
will be ruined because of them.
And it's all because of your help
and your courage.
We'll be waiting for you to return, okay?
[solemn music playing]
If you ever need me,
you know how to reach me.
Take care of yourself.
[unsettling music playing]
[suppressed gunshot]
Camia.
Forgive me.
Please forgive me, Camia.
[unsettling music continues]
I'm ready to face…
the punishment I deserve
for what I did to you.
Just grant me one favor.
Please forgive me.
What you're asking for
can't be given that easily.
[tense music playing]
You were deaf to my screams and pleas
when you were molesting me.
And when you tried to kill me.
Whatever punishment you expect
will never be enough
for the horror you put me through.
But…
But right now, I'm exhausted.
[tense music continues]
Exhausted from carrying the burden
of all the hardships I've gone through.
I used to think that…
I would never be reunited
with my daughter again.
I thought
that I would never get justice
for my husband's death.
And I thought
this town would never be
free of the Ardientes.
But now, I know…
that anything is possible.
As long as you have unwavering courage
and love in your heart.
I was able to forget
about Raul and what he did.
So, Tonio…
In time, I'll be able to
forgive you for what you did.
[breathes heavily]
Thank you, Camia.
Thank you very much.
[uplifting music playing]
[soft music playing]
Mom.
[chuckles]
This is it.
Our fight against the
Ardientes is almost over.
We took back power
and gave it to the people.
That's why we're free now, Mom.
You're right, dear.
But as long as Julio and Emilia
continue to roam free,
the justice we fought to seek
won't truly be served.
[soft music continues]
We're almost there, Mom.
We've come a long way.
I remember what Miss Prianka told me.
Seeking justice involves
a lot of patience.
And remember what Dad always used to say?
Fight, hope, and change.
And how change could only
be achieved through love.
Love for oneself,
love for others, and love for our nation.
For this town.
Lily.
I do hope this is the end…
and not the beginning
of an even bigger battle.
[soft music playing]
This is the end, Mom.
I'll make sure of it.
The Ardientes won't
just lose their mansion.
If they come back,
I'll make sure to take
everything they have,
so they can pay for all their crimes.
[reporter] Where are Julio Ardiente
and Emilia Ardiente-Torillo hiding?
Until now, the authorities
are still searching
for the two Ardientes.
Meanwhile, the position of…
The Ardientes have been defeated.
[reporter] Julio Ardiente fled
when the people revolted against him.
And since Vice Governor Mateo Ruiz
is in hiding for being
associated with a syndicate,
the provincial board member
with the most votes
will replace Julio Ardiente.
But the people want Diego Torillo,
Julio Ardiente's past election
rival, to be their governor.
[woman] I'm sorry, Lily. I didn't know.
I'm sorry for what I did.
That's all in the past.
[Edna] Miss Lily.
Governor.
Edna.
[Ronald] It's the governor.
Ma'am.
[Diego] How are you?
[Ronald] We're good, we're good.
Thank you.
At last, our parents are finally at peace.
[Ronald] Thanks to you,
we finally got the justice
we used to only dream about.
We all have the same wish…
because we've all been victims.
Our families were victims.
But you never backed down.
You never gave up the fight.
You and Diego taught us
to never be silenced
and to fight for what's right.
Because of that, we thank you
with all our hearts.
Even though the fight is over,
we hope you'll help us rebuild this town
so we can claim the hope
that our people
have been long searching for.
[Efren] Governor.
We're ready to help you with that.
You can count on us to be here for you.
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you for supporting my husband.
[tender music playing]
Whoa. I'm sorry--
Anna.
Jepoy.
The day we've been waiting for
finally arrived, huh?
I'm happy because we finally got
our long-awaited justice
against the Ardientes.
Thank you, Anna.
Thank you so much.
Really, thank you.
[ominous music playing]
[clears throat]
-Sorry to disturb your…
-[Jepoy] Natalie.
…platonic hug.
I just wanted to say thank you
because you knocked some sense into me.
And you still believed that
I have a little goodness
in my indigo heart.
Thanks to you, Lily Cruz,
and the rest of the gang,
the evil Ardientes are now
evicted out of this town.
But, you and I…
We still have unfinished business.
Natalie.
Anna's the one I love.
I've heard that before.
[chuckles]
Blah, blah, blah!
We all seem to want what we can't have.
Am I right, Mr. Madrigal?
[Natalie] Ouch!
[sighs]
Little Miss Anna…
Cherish it while it lasts,
-because tomorrow…
-Natalie.
…I'll be coming for him.
[tense music playing]
Anna…
[Jepoy] Anna, where are you going? Wait.
I'll be heading inside.
-I'll go with you.
-I'll do it.
[Jepoy] No, I'll do it.
I said I'll do it.
I can manage. You two stay here.
-Anna!
-[Jepoy mumbling]
Are you hitting on Anna?
-What do you think?
-I think you are.
[sighs]
So what if I am?
Just don't hurt her.
Don't worry. I'm not like you.
Commissioner?
Excuse me. Can I talk to the commissioner?
Look at their smiles.
They're all beaming.
That means that their dreams
finally came true.
That's why I ask you
to never allow the Ardientes
to take their dreams away.
Don't worry.
We will give the people
what they truly deserve.
[uplifting music playing]
[cheers and applause]
THE NEW ARDIENTE
DIEGO, THE REAL GOVERNOR
We've all gathered here today
to let each and every one of you
know the truth.
I'm ready to expose Julio Ardiente's lies
during the last election.
He paid me to manipulate the votes
so that he would win.
But the truth is,
the real winner was none
other than Diego Torillo.
[cheers and applause]
[bright music playing]
We will make an appeal to the court
to recount the votes
so that we can finally have
our town's true and rightful governor,
Diego Torillo!
[cheering, applause]
Diego is our governor!
Diego is the people's governor!
[crowd chants] Diego! Diego! Diego!
Diego! Diego! Diego! Diego!
[cheering and applause]
It's been months
since we finally got rid of
the people responsible
for destroying our town.
We can finally take back the power
that should've never belonged to them.
We will wipe away all
the filth left in our town.
Then, we will create together…
a new Poblacion Ardiente!
For the new Ardiente!
[crowd] For the new Ardiente!
[crowd chants] Diego! Diego! Diego!
-[uplifting music playing]
-[chanting continues]
[Lily] Thank you, Miss Prianka,
for making Ivy Aguas a part of my life.
The Ivy Aguas who is ready
to fight for what is right.
The Ivy Aguas who never gives up
no matter what life throws at her.
But most of all,
the Ivy Aguas who taught Lily Cruz
to be strong…
fierce, and powerful.
If it wasn't for you, Miss Prianka,
there wouldn't be
an Ivy Aguas or a Lily Cruz.
She wouldn't have been able to teach
the people of this town…
to go against the Ardientes.
Like how you taught me
to live my life with
righteousness in my heart.
[crowd chants] Diego! Diego! Diego! Diego!
[chanting continues]
[Diego] Nanny Loring, Uncle Pandoy…
I'm sure you're both happy now
that our fight is finally over.
We won.
[uplifting music playing]
Thank you for raising and guiding me.
If it wasn't for you both,
I wouldn't be who I am.
A man ready to fight for what is right.
[uplifting music continues]
Dad…
Thank you for always believing in me
as your son and as a man.
Despite everything we endured
because of the Ardientes,
you were still a good father to me.
Thank you very much.
And to everyone who sacrificed their lives
for this day to come.
Thank you very much.
I promise…
that no blood will be spilled
in this town ever again.
[uplifting music playing]
Thank you for all the times you saved me.
I didn't save you alone.
The townspeople were with me too.
It's their way of thanking you
for all the sacrifices
you've made for them.
For defending them from all the cruelty
they suffered at the hands
of the Ardientes.
[cheers and applause]
We'll make our dreams come true.
You and me…
we'll rebuild Poblacion Ardiente.
You are my life, Diego.
You are my governor.
You are the governor of this province.
Thank you as well, Mrs. Lily Torillo.
I love you so much.
I love you so much too, Diego.
I'll say it again.
You are my life and my governor.
[uplifting music playing]
[cheers and applause]
[cheers and applause continue]
[crowd chants] Governor Diego!
[chanting continues]
[Marlon] Governor Diego! Governor Diego!
[crowd continues chanting]
[uplifting music playing]
[uplifting music continues]
[chanting continues]
[crowd chants] Diego! Diego! Diego!
[gunshot]
[ominous music playing]
[screaming]
[gunshot]
[tense music playing]
[no audible dialogue]
[crowd screaming]
[tense music continues]
[melancholic music playing]
That was for Arnaldo.
[crowd clamoring]
-Diego!
-Find the shooter!
[crowd screaming]
-Diego!
Diego!
[Julio] Let's go!
[crowd screaming]
Help! Diego!
Help! Somebody, help!
Help him! Diego!
Lift him up!
Find the shooter!
[overlapping voices]
[crowd screaming]
[dramatic music playing]
[no audible dialogue]
[dramatic music continues]
Get out of the way!
Move! Move!
Out of the way!
[crowd screaming]
[overlapping voices]
[unintelligible]
[clamor continues]
[somber music playing]
[tense music playing]
Keep your eyes on the road, woman.
If you want to die,
then leave me out of it.
Where do we go now, Papa?
Everyone hates us.
We've got nowhere to run.
If you don't stop panicking,
then they really will catch up to us.
This isn't like your favorite TV show,
where they're all talk and no action.
But sure. Keep talking.
For once, help me think.
Where should we go?
Think hard!
Oh, my. Never mind, Emilia.
I never expected you to answer.
Just drive.
I already know where to go.
I know where you want to go, Papa.
I'm not as dumb as you think.
[tense music continues]
[somber music playing]
Diego.
-Diego.
-Ma'am, please stay here.
[somber music continues]
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
instrumental playing]
by Joey Ayala playing]
I'm begging You, Lord.
Please save Diego.
Please save my husband
and the governor of this province.
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
continues playing]
Our story won't end here.
Our dreams won't end here.
This can't be the end.
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
continues playing]
Mrs. Lily Torillo.
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
continues playing]
[music stops]
Diego?
Diego!
Diego, no. This can't be!
This isn't happening!
You can't do this to me, Diego!
Diego!
You can't do this to me!
You can't die on me!
Diego!
You can't do this to me!
[sobbing]
[wailing]
This can't be happening!
You can't just leave me!
You can't leave me!
You said you wouldn't leave me!
[sobbing]
This can't be!
Don't do this!
Please, Diego! Don't do this to me!
Please, please!
Diego, please!
Diego!
Diego, no! Wake up!
You can't die! Not like this!
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
by Joey Ayala playing]
[sobbing]
Diego!
How about me, Diego?!
How about me?
Why did you leave me?!
You said you wouldn't leave me!
[sobs]
Diego, please! Please! Please! Please!
Please, this can't be real.
This isn't happening.
Wake up, please.
Please, Diego.
Diego.
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
continues playing]
[Lily] Diego.
Diego.
[no audible dialogue]
It's Lily.
Everyone, it's Lily!
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
instrumental playing]
continues playing]
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
instrumental playing]
continues playing]
He's gone.
[crowd] What?
Diego's gone.
No! That's not true!
No! [sobs]
Diego!
No!
["Walang Hanggang Paalam"
by Joey Ayala playing]
continues playing]
[song fades]
[Lily] They had no right
to take Diego away from me.
I am the only king of Ardiente!
No one else!
Definitely not that dead bastard!
[Camia] No matter how grave
their crime was,
that doesn't give you the right
to take their lives.
[Julio] I killed Red Dragon.
[wailing]
[gunshots]
[theme music playing]